<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"
              "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.2/docbookx.dtd">
<article lang="en" id="art-dantonio-req-iu">
  <articleinfo>
    <title>User Interface of Donantonio</title>
    <subtitle>Specification of Software Requeriments</subtitle>
    <author>
      <firstname>Juan José</firstname>
      <surname>Amor</surname>
    </author>
    <author>
      <firstname>David</firstname>
      <surname>Escorial</surname>
    </author>
    <author>
      <firstname>Ismael</firstname>
      <surname>Olea</surname>
    </author>
    <pubdate>$Id: doc-ers_ieee830-donantonio-iusuario.en.xml,v 1.3 2002/11/18 21:03:03 manuelcanales Exp $</pubdate>
  </articleinfo>
  <sect1>
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>
This document is a Specification of Software Requeriments(SSR) for the 
client subsytem of the bibliographical automatic distributed publication 
system Donantonio. 
All this content has been elaborated considering the neededs
observed in the experience of the publication's authors in Internet. 
This specification has been structured being inspired by the directives 
given by the standard IEEE 
<emphasis remap="it">Recommended Practice for Software Requirements
Specification ANSI/IEEE 830 1998</emphasis>.
</para>
    <sect2>
      <title>Purpose</title>
      <para/>
      <para>
The object of the specification is to define in a clear and exact way all the functionalities
and restrictions of the system it wants to build. The document goes directed so much to the 
development equipment, like the members of the projects of free documentation and the community
of possible end users. This document will be the communication channel between the implied parts, 
taking part in its preparation, members from each part. This specification is subject to 
revisions by the implied parts, specially by the potentials usuaries, that will be picked up by 
successive versions of the document, until reach its approval. Once approved it will
serve as base to the equipment of development for the construction of the new system. 
</para>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>Scope of the system.</title>
      <para>
This system is required as a result of the increasing complication of 
the publication workings of documentation of free software. 
</para>
      <para>
It's evident the needed of a informatic system 
that it automates the publication workings of documents in Internet, 
in such form that are guaranteed the easy location of them and a fast 
availability to the users. 
</para>
      <para>
Using bibliographical norms it can become general the use and application 
of the system to any type of information susceptible to be classified. 
</para>
      <para>
The scope of the developed system reaches until the production of clients 
and servers for Donantonio, communication protocols between them and user interfaces; 
preferring the design of a system that can be embedded in other compatible 
applications so these can as well be compatible applications 
(clients, servers or interfaces) with Donantonio. 
</para>
    </sect2>
<sect2>
<title>Definitions, acronyms and abbreviations</title>

<sect3>
<title>Definitions</title>

<para>
<variablelist>

<varlistentry>
<term>Resource</term>
<listitem>
<para>
Element accessible through a URL susceptible 
to be classified bibliographically.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
<term>Scheme</term>
<listitem>
<para>
It describes the syntax of a description.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
<term>Description</term>
<listitem>
<para>
Instance of a scheme that it identifies by metadata, 
in a unequivocal way to a resource.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
<term>Library</term>
<listitem>
<para>
Collection of descriptions.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
<term>Server</term>
<listitem>
<para>
Node that takes care of donantonio queries.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
<term>Client</term>
<listitem>
<para>
Node that produce donantonio queries.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
<term>Query</term>
<listitem>
<para>
Request of a subgroup of descriptions 
expressed in a standardized language. 
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

</variablelist>	
</para>

</sect3>

<sect3>
<title>Acronyms</title>

<para>
<variablelist>

<varlistentry>
<term>SSR</term>
<listitem>
<para>
Specification of Software Requirements 
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
<term>GFDL</term>
<listitem>
<para>
GNU Free Documentation License
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
<term>GPL</term>
<listitem>
<para>
GNU Public License
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
<term>RDF</term>
<listitem>
<para>
Resource Description Framework, standard of the 
World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) for the codification 
and handling of metadata using the markup language XML. 
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
<term>URL</term>
<listitem>
<para>
Uniform Resource Locator, scheme used for
the localization of a internet resource.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry>
<term>XML</term>
<listitem>
<para>
eXtended Markup Language, standard of the W3C.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

</variablelist>
</para>

</sect3>

<sect3>
<title>Abbreviations</title>

<para>
They have not been defined.
</para>

</sect3>

</sect2>

<sect2>
<title>References</title>
      <para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
IEEE Recommended Practice for Software Requirements
Specification. ANSI/IEEE std. 830, 1998.

</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
Donantonio: bibliographic system for automatic distribuited publication. 
Specification of Software Requeriments. J.J. Amor,
D. Escorial e I. Olea, 2000.

</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
Donantonio Clients. Specification of Software Requeriments. J.J. Amor,
D. Escorial e I. Olea, 2000.

</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
Donantonio Servers. Specification of Software Requeriments. J.J. Amor,
D. Escorial e I. Olea, 2000.
</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>Document's General Vision</title>
      <para>
      This document is formed by three sections. 
This section is the Introduction and provides a general vision of the SSR. 
In the section 2 we give a general description of the system, 
with the purpose of knowing the main functions what must make the system, 
the data associate and the factors, restrictions, supposed and dependencies 
that affect the development, without enter in excessive details. 
In section 3 the requirements are defined in detail what must satisfy the system. 
</para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>General Description</title>
    <sect2>
      <title>Perspective of the product </title>
      <para>
The user interface will interact with clients donantonio, 
with a communication mechanism that will have to be defined.       
</para>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>System's functions</title>
      <sect3>
        <title>Access to the information</title>
        <para>
The user interface will have access to the local library of a Donantonio client, 
to consult the metadata contained there. 
</para>
      </sect3>
      <sect3>
        <title>Navigation's Mechanims</title>
        <para>
The user interface will include mechanisms that facilitate the navigation 
by the information of a Donantonio client. 
</para>
        <para>
          <emphasis remap="it">
          Note: Now I think it this is the less defined part... 
probably it's necessary to define here the interactive queries and all about that.
          </emphasis>
        </para>
      </sect3>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>user's Features</title>
      <para>
The user interfaces will have to be of intuitive use, 
easy to learn and simple to handle. 
The system will have to display a high degree of usability. 
The desirable would be that a new user became familiar with the 
system in very short time, being of immediate use for the functions 
of resources search.      
</para>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>Restrictions</title>
      <para>
The system will be free software (in agreement with the GNU-GPL 
license or similar) and will have to be free those components that it reuses. 
</para>
      <para>
The system will design according to a model client/server. 
</para>
      <para>
The system will base its communications on standard protocols of Internet. 
Internet.
</para>
      <para>
The different subsystems must have a simple design and implementation,
regardless of the platform or the programming language. 
</para>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>Suppositions and dependencies </title>
      <sect3>
        <title>Suppositions</title>
        <para>
It is assumed that the requirements described in this document are stable once 
is approved by the design team taking care of suggestions of the community. 
Any request of changes in the specification must be approved by the design team
and be managed by the same one. 
</para>
      </sect3>
      <sect3>
        <title>Dependencies</title>
        <para>
The Donantonio system works independently, with no need to communicate 
with other external systems, reason why there are no dependencies 
respect to other systems. 
</para>
      </sect3>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>
<sect1>
<title>Specific requirements </title>

<para>
In this section the it shows the functional requirements that will have 
to be satisfied by the system. All the requirements exposed here are 
ESSENTIAL, that is, a system would not be acceptable that does not satisfy 
some of the requirements presented here. 
These requirements have been specified considering, among others, 
the criterion of testing: given a requirement, 
it would have easily to be demonstrable if it is satisfied or not by the system. 
</para>

<para>
<emphasis remap="it">
Note: It is convenient to make the "requirements matrix", that confronts the 
requirements with the verification method. 
</emphasis>
</para>

<sect2>
<title>Functional requirements </title>
      <sect3>
        <title>REQ01: Library's Access</title>
        <para>
The user interface will be able to access to all the library 
of a client donantonio.         
</para>
      </sect3>
      <sect3>
        <title>REQ02: Library's Searches</title>
        <para>
The user interface will allow to make searches of descriptions, 
for which it can be specified total or partially the descriptions to look for.      
</para>
      </sect3>
      <sect3>
        <title>REQ03: Refinement</title>
        <para>
The user interface, after make a search and show the results to the user, 
will allow to refine the search, that means, to rewrite it from the actual 
making it more restrictive.         
</para>
      </sect3>
      <sect3>
        <title>REQ04: Resource's Access</title>
        <para>
The results of the search will include mechanisms that will allow 
to the user to ask for the making of a local copy of the referenced 
resource by the description. 
</para>
      </sect3>
      <sect3>
        <title>REQ05: Client's programming</title>
        <para>
The user will have mechanisms to program his client, that means, 
introduce in this one the donantonio queries that will make in the 
chosen servers, and when they will take place.         
</para>
      </sect3>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>External requirements of interfaces</title>
      <sect3>
        <title>User's Interfaces</title>
        <sect4>
          <title>REQ06: General requirement of the user interface</title>
          <para>
The designed user interface must have an hig degree of usability 
and have to be simple, fulfilling all the requirements specified. 
</para>
        </sect4>
      </sect3>
      <sect3>
        <title>Hardware's interfaces</title>
        <para>
They have not been defined 
</para>
      </sect3>
      <sect3>
        <title>Software's interfaces</title>
        <sect4>
          <title>REQ07: Communication with other modules </title>
          <para>
The communication with the clients donantonio will be made with protocols 
based on standards that allow to fulfill the other requirements of the system. 
</para>
        </sect4>
      </sect3>
      <sect3>
        <title>Communication's interfaces</title>
        <para>
They have not been defined 
</para>
      </sect3>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>Performance requirements</title>
      <sect3>
        <title>REQ09: Resources consumption</title>
        <para>
The complexity of the applications of user must be low, 
and consume few resources.         
</para>
      </sect3>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>Development requirements</title>
      <sect3>
        <title>REQ10: Life's Cycle.</title>
        <para>
The chosen cycle of life to develop the system will be 
the evolutionary prototype, so that changes and new 
functions can be incorporated easily.         
</para>
      </sect3>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>Technological requirements</title>
      <sect3>
        <title>REQ11: Bibliographical norms</title>
        <para>
The bibliographical schemes to use in the system will be expressed in RDF.         
</para>
      </sect3>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>Attributes</title>
      <sect3>
        <title>REQ12: Free Software</title>
        <para>
The system will be free software and, therefore, 
any software component that it also reuses will have to be free.         
</para>
      </sect3>
      <sect3>
        <title>REQ13: Portability </title>
        <para>
The system will be designed portable. It will have to be possible 
to implant donantonio applications in diverse languages and platforms.         
</para>
      </sect3>
      <sect3>
        <title>REQ14: Maintenance</title>
        <para>
The system is susceptible to be extended. 
Therefore it will have to be designed for easily maintenance, 
applying for his development the methodologies that it will be necessary.         
</para>
      </sect3>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>Other requirements</title>
      <para>taca taca</para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Apendices</title>
    <sect2>
      <title>License</title>
      <para>
Donantonio: Specification of Software Requirements 
</para>
      <para>
Copyright (C) 2000 Juan J. Amor, David Escorial and Ismael Olea.
</para>
      <para>
Permission is granted to reproduce total or partially this document, 
as long as the source is mentioned. 
Any modification of this document will have to be approved by the authors.       
</para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>
</article>
