<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?>

<appendix id="samba-smb.conf-completo">
	<title>Archivo de configuración <filename>/etc/samba/smb.conf</filename> - Completo -</title>

<programlisting><![CDATA[#
# Sample configuration file for the Samba suite for Debian GNU/Linux.
#
#
# This is the main Samba configuration file. You should read the
# smb.conf(5) manual page in order to understand the options listed
# here. Samba has a huge number of configurable options most of which
# are not shown in this example
#
# Any line which starts with a ; (semi-colon) or a # (hash)
# is a comment and is ignored. In this example we will use a #
# for commentary and a ; for parts of the config file that you
# may wish to enable
#
# NOTE: Whenever you modify this file you should run the command
# "testparm" to check that you have not many any basic syntactic
# errors.
#

#======================= Global Settings =======================

[global]

## Browsing/Identification ###

# Change this to the workgroup/NT-domain name your Samba server will part of
workgroup = GSRDOMAIN

# This sets the NetBIOS name by which a Samba server is known.
netbios name = TODOSCSI

# server string is the equivalent of the NT Description field
server string = SAMBA-LDAP PDC server

# Windows Internet Name Serving Support Section:
# WINS Support - Tells the NMBD component of Samba to enable its WINS Server
wins support = no

# WINS Server - Tells the NMBD components of Samba to be a WINS Client
# Note: Samba can be either a WINS Server, or a WINS Client, but NOT both
;   wins server = w.x.y.z

# This will prevent nmbd to search for NetBIOS names through DNS.
dns proxy = no

# What naming service and in what order should we use to resolve host names
# to IP addresses
name resolve order = lmhosts host wins bcast


#### Debugging/Accounting ####

# This tells Samba to use a separate log file for each machine
# that connects
log file = /var/log/samba/log.%m

# The value of the parameter (a astring) allows the debug level
# (logging level) to be specified in  the  smb.conf file.
# (passdb:5 auth:10 winbind:2)
log level = 0

# Put a capping on the size of the log files (in Kb).
# (0 means no limit)
max log size = 1000

# If you want Samba to only log through syslog then set the following
# parameter to 'yes'.
syslog only = no

# We want Samba to log a minimum amount of information to syslog. Everything
# should go to /var/log/samba/log.{smbd,nmbd} instead. If you want to log
# through syslog you should set the following parameter to something higher.
syslog = 0

# Do something sensible when Samba crashes: mail the admin a backtrace
panic action = /usr/share/samba/panic-action %d


####### Authentication #######

# "security = user" is always a good idea. This will require a Unix account
# in this server for every user accessing the server. See
# /usr/share/doc/samba-doc/htmldocs/ServerType.html in the samba-doc
# package for details.
security = user

# You may wish to use password encryption.  See the section on
# 'encrypt passwords' in the smb.conf(5) manpage before enabling.
encrypt passwords = true

# If you are using encrypted passwords, Samba will need to know what
# password database type you are using.
passdb backend = ldapsam:ldap://gsr.pt

# This parameter control whether or not Samba should obey PAM's
# account and session management directives. The default
# behavior is to use PAM for clear text authentication only and
# to ignore any account or session management. Note that Samba
# always ignores PAM for authentication in the  case  of
# encrypt passwords = yes.
obey pam restrictions = yes

# This is a username which will be used for access to services which
# are specified as "guest ok"
guest account = guest

# This is a list of users that should not be allowed to login to this service.
#   invalid users = root

# This boolean parameter controls whether Samba attempts to sync the Unix
# password with the SMB password when the encrypted SMB password in the
# passdb is changed.
unix password sync = yes

# For Unix password sync to work on a Debian GNU/Linux system, the following
# parameters must be set (thanks to Augustin Luton <aluton@hybrigenics.fr> for
# sending the correct chat script for the passwd program in Debian Potato).
;   passwd program = /usr/bin/passwd %u
passwd program = /usr/sbin/smbldap-passwd -o %u
passwd chat = *Enter\snew\sUNIX\spassword:* %n\n *Retype\snew\sUNIX\spassword:* %n\n .

# This boolean controls whether PAM will be used for password changes
# when requested by an SMB client instead of the program listed in
# 'passwd program'. The default is 'no'.
pam password change = no


####### LDAP-specific settings ########

# The ldap admin dn defines the Distinguished Name (DN) name used by Samba
# to contact the ldap server when retreiving user account information.
# The ldap admin dn is used in conjunction
# with the admin dn password stored in the private/secrets.tdb file.
# See the smbpasswd(8) man page for more information on how to accmplish this.
ldap admin dn = cn=admin,dc=gsr,dc=pt

# This parameter should contain the FQDN of the ldap directory server which
# should be queried to locate user account information.
;    ldap server = gsr.pt

# This option is used to control the tcp port number used to contact the
# ldap server. The default is to use the stand LDAPS port 636.
;   ldap port = 389

# This option is used to define whether or not Samba should use SSL when
# connecting to the ldap server. ('off', 'start_tls', or 'on' (default))
ldap ssl = star_tls

# This parameter specifies whether a delete operation in the ldapsam deletes
# the complete entry or only the attributes specific to Samba.
ldap delete dn = no

# This parameter specifies the RFC 2254 compliant LDAP search filter.
# The default is to match the login name with the uid attribute for
# all entries matching the sambaSamAccount objectclass.
# Note that this filter should only return one entry.
;   ldap filter = (&(uid=%u)(objectclass=sambaSamAccount))

# Specifies where user and machine accounts are added to the tree.
# Can be overriden by ldap user suffix and ldap machine suffix.
# It also used as the base dn for all ldap searches.
ldap suffix = dc=gsr,dc=pt

# This parameter specifies where users are added to the tree.
ldap user suffix = ou=people

# This parameters specifies the suffix that is used for groups when these
# are added to the LDAP directory.
ldap group suffix = ou=groups

# It specifies where machines should be added to the ldap tree.
ldap machine suffix = ou=machines


########## Printing ##########

# If you want to automatically load your printer list rather
# than setting them up individually then you'll need this
load printers = yes

# lpr(ng) printing. You may wish to override the location of the
# printcap file
;   printing = bsd
;   printcap name = /etc/printcap

# CUPS printing.  See also the cupsaddsmb(8) manpage in the
# cupsys-client package.
printing = cups

# When using [print$], root is implicitly a 'printer admin', but you can
# also give this right to other users to add drivers and set printer
# properties
printer admin = @domainprintoperator


######## File sharing ########

# Name mangling options
preserve case = yes


#### Domain Controller #######


# This integer value controls what level Samba advertises itself as for browse
# elections. The value of this parameter determines whether nmbd(8) has a
# chance of becoming a local master browser for the WORKGROUP in the
# local broadcast area.
os level = 80

# This boolean parameter controls if nmbd(8) is a preferred master browser
# for its workgroup.
preferred master = yes

# Domain Master specifies Samba to be the Domain Master Browser. If this
# machine will be configured as a BDC (a secondary logon server), you
# must set this to 'no'; otherwise, the default behavior is recommended.
domain master = yes

# This option allows nmbd(8) to try and become a local master browser
# on a subnet.
local master = yes

# If set to yes, the Samba server will act as a Primary Domain Controller
# (PDC) for  the  workgroup  it  is  in.
domain logons = yes

# This  parameter specifies the home directory where roaming profiles
# (NTuser.dat etc files for Windows NT) are stored.
logon path = \\%L\profiles\%u

# This parameter specifies the local path to which the home directory
# will be connected and is only used by NT Workstations.
logon drive = H:

# This  parameter  specifies the home directory location when a Win95/98
# or NT Workstation logs into a Samba PDC.
logon home = \\%L\%u\.profile

# This parameter specifies the batch file (.bat) or NT command file
# (.cmd) to be downloaded and run  on a machine when a user successfully
# logs in.
;   logon script = logon.cmd
logon script = 

# Users and groups allowed to be 'Domain Admins'
;   domain admin group = @domainadmins


############ Misc ############

# Using the following line enables you to customise your configuration
# on a per machine basis. The %m gets replaced with the netbios name
# of the machine that is connecting
;   include = /home/samba/etc/smb.conf.%m

# Most people will find that this option gives better performance.
# See smb.conf(5) and /usr/share/doc/samba-doc/htmldocs/speed.html
# for details
# You may want to add the following on a Linux system:
#         SO_RCVBUF=8192 SO_SNDBUF=8192
socket options = TCP_NODELAY SO_RCVBUF=8192 SO_SNDBUF=8192
winbind uid = 10000-20000
winbind gid = 10000-20000

# When filling out the user information for a Windows NT user,
# the winbindd(8) daemon uses this parameter to fill in the login
# shell for that user.
template shell = /bin/bash

# This parameter specifies what OS ACL semantics should be
# compatible with. Possible values are winnt for Windows NT 4,
# win2k for Windows 2000 and above and auto. If you specify auto,
# the value for this parameter will be based upon the version
# of the client. There should be no reason to change this
# parameter from the default.
acl compatibility = Auto

# Using smbldap-tools to add machines
add user script = /usr/sbin/smbldap-useradd.pl -w %u


#======================= Share Definitions =======================

[homes]
comment = Home Directories

# This controls whether this share is seen in the list of
# available shares in a net view and in the browse list.
browseable = no
read only = no

# File creation mask is set to 0700 for security reasons. If you want to
# create files with group=rw permissions, set next parameter to 0775.
create mask = 0700

# Directory creation mask is set to 0700 for security reasons. If you want to
# create dirs. with group=rw permissions, set next parameter to 0775.
directory mask = 0700

[netlogon]
comment = Network Logon Service
path = /home/samba/netlogon
share modes = no
guest ok = yes
write list = @domainadmins

[profiles]
comment = User's Profiles
path = /home/samba/profiles
read only = no
browseable = no
create mask = 0600
directory mask = 0700
guest ok = yes

[printers]
comment = All Printers
path = /var/spool/samba
browseable = no
printable = yes
printer admin = root, @domainprintoperator
;   create mask = 0700

# Windows clients look for this share name as a source of downloadable
# printer drivers
[print$]
comment = Printer Drivers
path = /var/lib/samba/printers
write list = root, @domainprintoperator

[tmp]
comment = Temporal
read only = no
path = /tmp

[cdrom]
comment = Samba server's CD-ROM
locking = no
path = /cdrom
guest ok = yes]]></programlisting>
</appendix>
